I wanted to make a video on the sharing
economy I think I love so much of the
sharing economy I love things that were
around before the term was coined like
libraries love libraries I also think
that the sharing economy has been
co-opted by capitalism that platforms
like Airbnb and uber try to tug at our
heartstrings like look we're using less
resources and the truth is they are they
are but they're not necessarily
listening to the people using those
resources and making it not empowering
the individual and why would they there
gave me they are the old paradigm but we
can create the platforms that help us
create a real honest sharing economy or
were sharing in resources we're creating
the libraries of everything including
knowledge including 3d knowledge so you
can print your own things and including
the platforms to share in labor like
what uber does but make it so that it is
asking the people doing the labor how do
we make this easier for you how do we
make it give you more of an incentive
without necessarily increasing them on
the monetary contribution of the people
using your labor in the instance of our
version of uber that would be oh you
have mileage on your car you have you
hated you need car insurance you need in
cities and spaces where it's possible
doing cooperatively owned like buying a
bulk package of car insurance having
mechanic shops that you can bring your
car into the services at cost bulk
buying gas if that's an option like
looking up ways to make it cheaper and
cheaper getting health insurance for for
the drivers because uber saves a lot of
money by making them contract workers
and we can basically unionize our labor
force without that tension between
unions and managers we are sitting down
and having a conversation of what makes
this meaningful work to you what would
make you want to drive more
and of course part of that it's gonna be
monetary compensation they're not doing
it just for the fun of it mostly and so
and how do we also listen to the
passengers and say what would make this
better for you pain less money okay how
can we make it so the drivers make more
money and the passengers make less money
we can co-create that together with
ride-sharing with in contributing our
data so we can find better paths that
the vehicles can take taking more people
that that also honor that it's not
public transit that it's not like you're
going from point A to point B we could
just do more you can do more together
creating a sharing economy in
information that we have access to the
same information so we can build the
foundations on that that's a little more
of a stretch the sharing economy would
be kind of I got and sharing in the
people that we get to create the
connections that we want to have access
to if there are projects you would love
to work on whether that's music or
science or discovery being able to find
your people we can create the platforms
for all of that we're gonna create the
platform and those platforms can work
together so that when one is created
whether through us or somebody else we
can get people to it is it a platform we
want to exist in the world let's get
people to that platform if it's a
platform we want to create it doesn't
exist in the world how do we create it
and then how do we constantly be looking
for ways to improve it and empower
people to bring their voice to that
process how do we make the entire thing
fun and simple so that people want to
look for ways to collaborate and want to
be part of collaboration that's how we
create win-win scenarios when we look at
a new paradigm of every new person is in
addition to the to the intellect
intellectual intellectual interweb to
the to the resource interweb like to
have all of those nodes connected brings
every time someone new comes on it
brings more power unlike uber because at
uber a new driver coming on means that
there's more supply and there
or the drivers are gonna make less
creating more drivers means that we have
more nodes more people to say what is
going to work and not work and to
constantly be asking what would make it
better for both parties
while not necessarily making it an
increase in the dollar amount from the
passenger to a dollar amount increase
for the for the driver there are ways to
exponentially grow our value without
needing an increase in hourly wage and
together we can find those ways and
co-create them so how well I did not
explain the shared economy but this
video was a response to a comment on one
of my previous videos someone talking
about the sharing economy and the issues
in it and yes there are a lot of issues
in the sharing economy and when we
co-create it together we can minimize
the issues and maximize the reward and
the potential for environment for less
environmental impact way more human
connection and just a better life on
this planet take care and I will see you
the next time I'm on a better world is
on its way and I'm gonna need to figure
out a new tagline that doesn't say see
you tomorrow
take care